So, how does this change the way we approach new problems?
これによって問題を解決する アプローチはどう変わりますか？
A few years ago, we found that certain types of queries were becoming more common.
数年前 特定の検索ワードが 増えたことに気づきました
Japanese toys in San Francisco,
サンフランシスコで買える 日本製のおもちゃ
live lobster in Kissimmee,
キシミーの活ロブスター
vegan donuts near me.
近くのヴィーガンドーナツ
These are hard queries, local queries.
地域情報を探す難しい検索ワードです
People are not looking for websites,
人々はウェブサイトではなく
but actually businesses on a map.
実際の店舗を探しているのです
Well, we could write rules for each of these,
1つずつルールを書いてもいいのですが
but it becomes unwieldy rather quickly.
それではすぐに手に負えなくなります
So, let's see how we approach it from a machine learning perspective.
そこで 機械学習の観点からアプローチします
We start by thinking about how to collect the data to make it
ML問題にするためのデータ収集から始めます
an ML problem. Let's look at an example.
例を見てみましょう
The query, coffee near me.
検索ワードは「近くのコーヒー」とします
The idea behind machine learning is to take a bunch of
機械学習の考え方は多数のサンプルを取得して
examples and convert that knowledge into future predictions.
その知識を未来の予測に変換することです
When you search for "coffee near me," what
「近くのコーヒー」を検索した場合
are the examples that you are collecting that you're converting into knowledge?
どのようなサンプルを集めて 知識に変換しますか？
What is the future prediction?
未来の予測は何ですか？
The prediction is quite straightforward.
予測は単純です
There are two options.
2つの選択肢があります
Bill's Diner carries coffee and it's only three minutes away.
ほんの3分先に コーヒーを出す食堂がありますが
However, there's a gourmet coffee shop just two minutes more.
さらに2分行けば 本格的なカフェがあります
And we rather think you'd prefer the coffee shop to the sandwich shop.
あなたは食堂ではなく カフェを選ぶと予測します
On the other hand,
一方で
if the gourmet coffee shop is across the bridge,
本格的なカフェが橋の向こうなら
we probably will send you to the diner instead.
食堂に誘導します
Or if the diner typically takes 10 minutes to serve
もしくは食堂でコーヒーが出るのに 10分かかったり
coffee or doesn't have takeaway coffee so that you have to sit down and eat,
テイクアウトがなく 店で飲む必要があるなら
then perhaps a 15-minute walk is what you'd prefer.
15分歩いたほうが良さそうです
How far is too far?
どのくらいが遠すぎる距離ですか？
How much is the rating of the restaurant and the time it takes to serve you?
食堂の評価や コーヒーが出るまでの時間はどうですか？
How much do all of these matter?
これらはどれほど重要ですか？
Rather than guessing and having a whole bunch of rules,
推測して多数のルールを書くよりも
we'd rather have users telling us.
ユーザーに聞いた方がよさそうです
So, we look at a bunch of data and do a trade-off.
それで多数のデータを見て 比較します
Distance versus quality of coffee,
距離とコーヒーの質
service time versus quality of coffee, etcetera.
コーヒーが出るまでの時間とコーヒーの質 などです
But let's now just consider distance.
ここでは距離のみを考えましょう
Where do you get this data?
データをどこで入手しますか？
As an AI-first company,
AIを優先する企業としては
we might start with heuristics,
ヒューリスティックスで 始めるかもしれませんが
but we do so with the mindset that we're going to throw away
ユーザーの好みに関する 十分なデータを入手した時点で
the heuristics just as soon as we have enough data about user preferences.
ヒューリスティックスは止めます
What we need are examples.
それにはサンプルが必要です
Remember, example equals labelled data.
サンプルとはラベル付きのデータでしたね
Here, the input is the distance to the shop and
ここでの入力は店までの距離で
the label is "Does the user like the result or does he not?"
ラベルは「ユーザーは結果を好むか否か」です
So, we take an example of a shop one kilometer away and the user says,
1キロ先の店に対してあるユーザーが
"Great, I'll go one kilometer for a great coffee."
「1キロ先まで美味しいコーヒーを 飲みに行きたい」と言います
And then we ask another user whether they'd go three kilometers and they say,
他のユーザーには3キロ先まで行くか聞き
"I don't even like gourmet coffee."
「そもそも本格的なコーヒーは嫌い」と 言われます
So, we aggregate a bunch of different examples
このようにさまざまなサンプルを集め
until eventually we realize it's so far away that nobody wants to go.
誰も行かないような距離になるまで続けます
And then, we try to fit our model.
そこでモデルの適合を試みます
So, machine learning is about collecting the appropriate data
このように機械学習とは適切なデータ収集の後
and then finding this right balance of good learning and trusting the examples.
効果的な学習とデータの信頼性との 正しいバランスを探ることです